迈克 · 诺斯: 接下来我们要讨论的是五分钟
&gt;&gt; Mike North: The next thing we're going
to talk about is a little five-minute
类型系统描述。
description of type systems.
以及如何分辨这两者的区别并利用它们
And how you can tell the difference and
take advantage
类似打字稿和类似 Java 的东西之间的区别。
of the difference between something
like TypeScript and something like Java.
因此，类型系统可以归结为等价类型的问题。
So, type systems come down to this
question of type equivalents.
当我们看到一些错误消息时，我们看到的也是同样的东西
And that is the same thing we were looking
at when we saw some error messages
和赋值的左右手有关，对吗？
that related to the left-hand and
the right-hand of an assignment, right?
这是打字稿试图找出这个值，你正在尝试
That's TypeScript trying to figure
out is this value you're trying to
赋值等价于你要赋值的变量的类型。
assign equivalent to this type of
the variable you're assigning it to.
同样的事情也会发生在，你试图传递一个参数给函数的时候。
And the same thing happens when you're
trying to pass an argument to a function.
就把它想象成一个试图穿过一个洞的物体。
Just think of it like an object
trying to pass through a hole.
你希望方桩适当地穿过一个方孔。
You want the square peg passing
through a square hole as appropriate.
所以，真正的问题是，我们能不能把 x 看作是一个 htmlinputement？
So really, it's about can we
regard x as an HTMLInputElement?
类型系统，比如 Java 和几乎所有的类型化语言,
Nominal type systems, like Java and
almost every typed language out there,
他们会根据 x 是否是一个实例来回答这个问题
they would answer the question
based on whether x is an instance
不管你要找的是什么类型的。
of a class named whatever
the type you're looking for.
因此，这需要您将所有代码设置在一个公平的
So this would require you to have
all of your code set up in a fairly
面向对象的方式，你有构造函数。
object-oriented way where
you have constructors.
主要处理类和类的实例
And you're dealing primarily
with instances of classes and
你在传东西。
you're passing things around.
这不一定是 JavaScript 代码的编写方式。
This isn't necessarily how
JavaScript code is written.
这就需要我们进行大量的改写，几乎所有的东西
And this would require us to do a lot of
rewriting and to make almost everything
一个类和一个实例，以便具有具体名称的工厂。
a class and an instance in order to
have factories with specific names.
这样我们就可以利用类型的优势。
So that we could take advantage of types.
是一个结构类型的系统,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: TypeScript is
a structural type system,
他们只关心物体的形状。
they only care about
the shape of an object.
哪些属性名称和类型是允许用于这些属性的，对吗？
Which is property names and types that
are allowed for those properties, right?
所以它只关心对象的结构。
So it only cares about
the structure of an object.
所以，如果我们有一个汽车的数据结构，我们可以称之为汽车。
So, if we had like a data structure for
a car, we could call it car.
但实际上，我们所关心的只是它有一种叫做 make 的特性,
But really, all we care about is the fact
that it has properties called make,
型号及年份，而该等型号及年份均属适当类别。
model and
year that are of the appropriate types.
函数也是如此。
Same goes for functions.
我们实际上只关心参数和返回类型。
We really only care about
the arguments and the return type.
如果你创建了一个完全不同的函数来满足这些条件,
And if you create a totally different
function that meets those criteria,
结果就是类型等价。
that will end up being type equivalent.
在需要使用该类型的地方，这将是可用的。
That will be usable where you
need that type to be used.
我必须指出，这是一个需要理解的重要概念
And I should point out that this is
an important concept to understand in
打字稿。
TypeScript.
但是如果你在 JavaScript 中有一致的形状。
But also if you have consistent
shapes in JavaScript.
而且你可以避免给已经被大量使用的对象引入新的属性。
And you avoid introducing new properties
to objects that have been heavily used.
你最终在 JavaScript 运行时有了一个更好的机会,
You end up having a better
shot at JavaScript run times,
比如 V8优化你的代码。
like V8 optimizing your code.
使用了术语 wider and
&gt;&gt; Mike North: TypeScript
uses the term wider and
缩小到可以描述特异性的程度。
narrower to describe
a level of specificity.
毫无疑问，你会遇到这样的人，他们使用更宽、更窄、更多的词汇
And you'll no doubt come across
someone who uses wider, narrower, and
我今天就开始用这些术语。
I'm gonna start using these terms today.
但是这里的图表可以帮助你理解我们的意思。
But here is the diagram to help you
understand what we mean by this.
最宽的类型是 any，它允许任何可能的值。
The widest type is any and
it allows for any possible value.
只要把它想象成，任意一个被允许的值的集合是无穷大的。
And just think of it as the set of allowed
values for any is infinitely wide.
它可以取任何东西，几乎是无穷大。
It can just take absolutely anything,
it’s almost infinity.
现在，如果我说，我想要一个数组，任何一个数组。
Now, if I said, I want an array,
any array at all.
我不在乎这个数组中的值类型,
I don't care what type of
value is in this array,
那是窄的类型，对吗？
that would be a narrower type, right?
我们不再是无限宽广了。
We're not infinitely wide anymore.
这组值，如果你把它们排成一行,
The set of values,
if you line them up end to end,
会更窄，但还是很宽。
it would be narrower,
still pretty wide though.
我们可以更具体地说，这个数组可以是任意长度的,
And we could get even more specific and
say this array can be of arbitrary length,
但它必须只包含字符串。
but it must only contain strings.
然后你可以说，但它必须是长度为3的。
And then you could say, but
it must be of length three.
但是这些字符串可以是任何东西。
But those strings can be anything at all.
然后我们可以通过非常具体地说明
And then we could get narrower still
by being very specific about what
这些值可能是某些字符串。
certain strings these values might be.
现在如果我们有一个可以操作任何数组的函数。
Now if we had a function that
could operate on any array.
我们可以查看数组类型，它下面的任何内容,
We could look at the array type,
and anything below it,
任何窄一点的都可以用，只是更具体一点。
anything narrower than that will be
fine to use, it's just more specific.
我们始终可以将必须保持大小为3的三个字符串的数组视为。
We can always regard an array of three
strings that must remain of size three.
我们总是可以把它看作一个任意的字符串数组，或者
We can always regard that as
an arbitrary array of strings, or
作为任何数组，或者任何值，对吗？
as an array of anything,
or as any value, right?
所以狭窄的数值总是可以通过较宽的洞来适应。
So narrower values can always
fit through the wider hole.
我就是这么想的。
That's the way I kind of think of this.
但是如果你想要一个字符串数组,
But if you wanted to have
specifically an array of strings,
如果你有一个任意数组，你就得想办法缩小这个数组的范围。
and you had an array of any, you'd have
to find a way to narrow that type.
并且确认只有正确的东西才能通过。
And to validate that only
the correct thing fits through.
这就是我们所说的“宽”和“窄”。
So this is what we mean by wider and
narrower.
宽是非常一般的，狭是非常具体的。
Wide is very general,
narrow is extremely specific.
当我们使用空数组初始化数组时，会遇到这种 never 类型。
We run into this never type when we were
initializing an array with an empty array.
永远是无限狭窄的，它从字面上看不能容纳任何价值。
Never is infinitely narrow,
it literally can hold no value.
我的意思是，它可以容纳一个从来没有，但它就像循环推理，对不对？
I mean, it can hold a never, but
it is like circular reasoning, right?
你认为它就像没有洞，没有什么可以真正通过。
You think of it like there is no hole,
nothing can really pass through.
这是没有什么和不可能的，或不可达到的，这样想想
It is nothing and impossible, or
unreachable, think of it that way